Nkenge Touré Papers, circa 1968-2014
Sophia Smith Collection
Nkenge Touré papers
circa 1968-2014
Touré, Nkenge
MS 563
11 boxes (5.25 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
Political activist; Health reformer; Feminist; Civil rights activist. The papers consist of extensive files pertaining to Nkenge Touré's activism in health reform and civil and political rights for African American women. SisterSong Women of Color Reproductive Justice Collective and the D.C. Rape Crisis Center are well-documented, as are many conferences and workshops in which Touré participated. Touré's international work in these fields is also represented, and there is a small amount of material about the Black Panthers. Tapes of Touré's radio program, In Our Voices, are also included.
Nkenge Touré is a self-proclaimed "Diva of Decent." She was born Anita Stroud on March 5, 1951 to parents Juanita King and John Stroud. She has two younger brothers. Stroud grew up in public housing in Baltimore, Maryland, in a female-headed household.
At Eastern High School in the late 1960's, Stroud and a few girls founded an underground student activist group called the Black Voice to protest institutionalized racism in her majority white school. This time period marked the beginning of Stroud's activist life, as well as her first experiences with police brutality at the age of seventeen. The members of the Black Voice were forcibly arrested for their role in organizing what became a large-scale student strike of local schools. Stroud was given the option to receive her high school diploma only if she apologized for her activism. She refused, and later earned a GED. In her latter high school years, Stroud became involved with Baltimore's Soul School and the Black Panther Party, which she went on to join. She was a member of the Party from 1970-1973, working in several chapters, including Washington, D.C.
She married John Wesley Stevens, also a Party member, and they took the names Nkenge and Patrice Touré. They had two daughters, Trina Stevens and Kianga Stroud. When many of the members of the D.C. Black Panthers chapter went to California to work on the mayoral and City Council campaigns of Bobby Seale and Elaine Brown in 1973, Touré and her husband stayed behind in D.C. They founded Save the People (STP) and ran the Education for Liberation Bookstore on 9th and H. Save The People was asked to sell The Black Panther, the Party's newspaper in the party's absence as well as continue providing free meals, health care, and education to the community.
In 1974 she became the second Black woman to join the staff of the D.C. Rape Crisis Center. Touré worked at the Center for thirteen years, serving as General Administrator and Director of Community Education. She wrote anti-sexual assault curricula for students, spoke widely, worked on their rape crisis hotline, and appeared regularly in the media. She pioneered DC's Anti-Rape Week and Coalition for a Hassle Free Zone, an anti-street harassment campaign. Nkenge and Patrice Touré were divorced in 1979.
Touré was one of the co-founders of the Women's Section of the National Black United Front, defending women's rights within Black Nationalist politics and ensuring their issues were represented. In 1982, Touré co-founded the International Council of African Women (ICAW) with Loretta Ross to prepare a delegation of American women to attend the 1985 United Nations Conference on Women in Nairobi, Kenya. ICAW was the primary source providing information, support, and encouragement to African American women to organize delegations and attend the "Herstoric" conference. She was President of the D.C. Chapter of the National Black Women's Health Project (now Black Women's Health Imperative) from 1987-1994.
Since leaving the D.C. Rape Crisis Center in 1988, Touré has hosted her own weekly radio show, "In Our Voices," which serves as a platform for the voices and issues of women on D.C. radio station WPFW. She and guests discuss issues from the perspective that any issue is a women's issue. Also at WPFW, Touré served as the Executive Producer of Sophie's Parlor, the oldest women's music and politics collective in the United States. Since 1990 she has been working with women substance abusers, women living with HIV/AIDS, women and children residing in transitional housing, and babies born with HIV. Touré has been a weekend volunteer and served on the board of My Sister's Place, a shelter for battered women and their children, and on the board of the National Center for Human Rights Education. She has been active with SisterSong Women of Color Reproductive Justice Collective.
Touré has received numerous awards for her ongoing hard work and commitment to human rights and justice for women of color in the D.C. area and worldwide. Her writings on these subjects can be read in a number of publications including Aegis and Vital Signs. She has also spoken widely at rallies, speak outs, and conferences. She is committed to ending all forms of violence against women--psychological, cultural, racial, economic, state, sexual, and physical. She has described herself as both passionate and compassionate, a mother, grandmother, feminist, and warrior for her people.
The Nkenge Touré papers consist of 5.25 linear ft. of files pertaining to Touré's activism in health reform and civil and political rights for African American women. The files are primarily related to her professional and public life. Types of material include brochures, correspondence, news clippings, newsletters, notes, photographs, posters, publications, journal and newspaper articles, and audiocassettes. The papers are arranged in seven series:
I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS AND PHOTOGRAPHS
II. CORRESPONDENCE
III. CONFERENCES
IV. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS
V. SPEECHES AND WRITINGS
VI. SUBJECT FILES
VII. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS
OVERSIZE MATERIALS
The bulk of the papers date from 1980 to 2004 and focus on Touré's organizational work, conference attendance, and radio broadcasting. Touré's thirteen years at the D.C. Rape Crisis Center are well documented, as is the founding of the International Council of African Women (ICAW), her work with SisterSong Women of Color Reproductive Justice Collective, and her role in organizing the 2004 March for Women's Lives. There is a small amount of material on the Black Panther Party, including a scrapbook of photographs and news clippings from the late 1960's, the time of the beginning of Touré's activism. There is extensive material on Touré's shows on Washington, D.C.'s WPFW radio, including many scripts from and audiocassettes of her long-running show "In Our Voices." Her attendance and presentations at many conferences is well documented. The papers also contain several essays and many original speeches and workshop outlines.
The Papers are open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection without any additional restrictions.
Periodic additions to collection are expected and may not be reflected in this record.
Nkenge Touré began donating her Papers to the Sophia Smith Collection in 2007. Periodic additions are expected and may not be reflected in this finding aid.
Related can be found in the collections:
SisterSong Women of Color Reproductive Justice Collective
Black Women's Health Imperative
Loretta J. Ross Papers
Interview with Nkenge Touré in the Voices of Feminism Oral History Project
Abused women -- Services for -- United States -- History; African American women -- Biography -- Sources; African American women health reformers -- History -- Sources; African American women -- Political activity -- Sources; African Americans -- Civil rights -- History -- Sources; Birth control -- Law and legislation -- History -- Sources; Feminists -- United States -- Biography -- Sources; Rape -- United States -- History -- Sources; Reproductive rights -- United States -- History -- Sources; Women's health services -- United States -- History -- Sources; Women in radio broadcasting -- United States -- History; Touré, Nkenge; Black Women's Health Imperative -- History; D.C. Rape Crisis Center -- History; National Black Women's Health Network; SisterSong Women of Color Reproductive Health Collective
Appendix I. "In Our Voices" Scripts
1. 2/16/88: Sheroes Part II
2. 12/1/88: Mail Order Brides/Sex Tourism
3. 12/8/88: Mental/Spiritual/Physical Health/ Holiday Blues
4. 1/26/89: Women in Southern Africa
5. 2/27/89: Adoption
6. 3/2/89: Commission for Women
7. 3/9/89: Homelessness
8. 3/9/89: Reproductive Rights/April 9th March
9. 3/9/89: Male Roundtable
10. 3/16/89: Women in Third World Countries
11. 3/16/89: African Concepts of Education
12. 4/6/89: PMS
13. 4/27/89: New Global Economy Part 1
14. 5/4/89: Part 2 Visioning New Global Economy
15. 5/5/89: Interview with bell hooks
16. 6/1/89: Everyday Theatre Youth Ensemble
17. 6/8/89: International Council of African Women
18. 6/15/89: Refugee Women in Development
19. 6/22/89: Psychology of Beauty
20. 6/22/89: Interview with Ayo Handy, creator of the Success Series
21. 6/29/89: Independent Schools Interview
22. 8/29/89: Commission for Women Interview Update
23. 9/19/89: Women Newspaper Editors
24. 9/26/89: Street Harassment and Confrontation
25. 10/3/89: Teen Pregnancy
26. 10/6/89: Male/Female Relationships
27. 10/11/89: Women's Health Roundtable
28. 11/89: Rape & Incest
29. circa 1989: Black Women Filmmakers
30. 1/9/90: Campaign for Democracy & Independence
31. 3/5/93: Black Women Sheroes
32. 10/16/98: "The Whipper Woman & Open Mike"
33. 10/30/98: "Interview Dr. Grace Cornish, 10 bad choices that ruin Black women's lives"
34. 11/27/98: "The Rise of Female Detectives in Literature and the Social Implications"
35. 11/17/?: Abortion Rights and the Title 10 Initiative
36. n.d.: AIDS
37. n.d.: Male Roundtable
38. n.d.: Reparations
39. n.d: Peers Program
40. n.d.: A.M.O., Black Theology
41. n.d.: Resistance Conspiracy Case
42. n.d.: Youth Violence
43. n.d.: Women in the Arts
44. n.d.: W.M.S.
45. n.d.: Reproductive Rights
46. n.d.: D.C. Advisory Council of Women Offenders, Women in Prison
47. n.d.: D.C. Statehood
48. n.d.: Women Slaves
49. n.d.: West African Research Association
Appendix IIa. Titles of Speeches and Writings
1. "African Women Rising: The World Decade on Women," n.d.
2. "Black Women and the Question of Sexual Assault," n.d
3. "Call to Unity," 3/8/87
4. "Closing Comments," n.d.
5. "Comments: At Rally Against New Diagnostic Categories…," 5/12/86
6. "Dispelling the Myths & Rethinking the Issues," 5/24/87
7. "Focus on Women of Color," 12/8/84
8. "Friends of Azania," 2/26/84
9. "From Cries & Whispers to Action - Black Women & AIDS," n.d.
10. "Geraldine Smith," n.d.
11. "How Reaganomics Have Affected Women," 4/12/84
12. "Impact of Nairobi on Black Women and the Family," 3/16/86
13. "Nicaragua Program," 11/17/84
14. "Opening" [Testimony on the D.C. Prevention of Domestic Violence Act], 1989
15. "Organizing Now and For the Future," 4/25/1981
16. "Peace & Bread Workshops," n.d.
17. "Plenary Session: In Celebration of Our Common Language," 3/11/84
18. "Preparations for Kenya," 12/8/84
19. "Prog. Jan. 19, 84…," 1/19/84
20. "Racism, Sexism, Violence: the Connection," n.d.
21. "Sexism," n.d.
22. "Sisters United in Struggle," n.d.
23. "South Africa: The Link," 1/26/85
24. "Take Back Nite March Speech," 9/13/86
25. "Theory of Community Education," 5/81
26. "Violence Against Black Women: Breaking the Silence," n.d.
27. "Allow me to welcome each of you," n.d.
28. "And that's cool," n.d.
29. "And thru that," n.d.
30. "By now many women are aware," n.d.
31. "First I want to thank the members of the institute," n.d.
32. "Questions," n.d.
33. "The overall encompassing theme for this panel," n.d.
34. "Upon reading grand juries," n.d.
35. "What needs to be understood," n.d.
Appendix IIb. Speech Outlines
1. "ARW - Outline: Focus on Black Women," n.d.
2. "Exploring the Politics of Violence Against Women," n.d.
3. "Forum Speech Outline," n.d.
4. "Outline: Black Women in Particular," 5/31/87
5. "Outline: Focus on Black Women," n.d.
6. "Outline: Organizing Against Sexual Assault in the Black Community," n.d.
7. "Outline: Rape & Raising Consciousness," n.d.
8. "Outline: Talking w/teens about sexuality," n.d.
9. "Outline: Women's Struggle for Jobs, Peace, and Justice," n.d.
Appendix IIc. Conference / Workshop Outlines
1. "Eco Panel Presentation," n.d.
2. "Issues for Women of Color," n.d.
3. "The Nexus of Racism & Sexual Violence in the African American Community," n.d.
4. "Organ. Efforts," n.d.
5. "Outline," n.d.
6. "Outline," n.d.
7. "Outline- Kenya: World Decade for Women," n.d.
8. "Outline - Overview/History of Conference & Decade," 7/14/84
9. "Outstanding Black Women," n.d.
10. "Overcoming Working in Isolation in Women's Organs.," 5/15/87
11. "Overview of Third World Women and Violence," n.d.
12. "Overview of Women of Color Organizations," 5/16/87
13. "Panel Outline," 10/19-20/85
14. "Society for International Development/Women in Development," 3/18/86
15. "Workshop Outline" (Rape Shatters Lives Conf.), 4/4-5/?
16. "Workshop Outlines," n.d.
17. "Workshop Topic: The Impact of the International Decade for Women…," n.d.
Appendix IId. Writings
1. "Dialogue with Dessie," pg. 9, FAAR & NCN newsletter (Aegis), July/August 1978
2. "Report on the First National Third World Women's Conference on Violence," pg. 70, Aegis, Summer/Autumn 1980
3. "Organizing Now and for the Future," 4/2/1981, Symposium on "Feminism and the Critique of Capitalism"
4. "Report from the First National Conference on Third World Women and Violence: An Overview of Third World Women and Violence," 1981
5. "Report from the First National Conference on Third World Women and Violence: Third World Women and Rape," 1981
6. STAYING SAFE Sexual Assault: How to Protect Yourself, written with Elizabeth M. Ozer, 1984, D.C. Rape Crisis Center
7. "Networking African Women: How?"
8. "Report from Nairobi," Aegis, No. 40, 1986
9. "18th Women's Law Conference, WDC," March 20, 1987
10. "Sexism Has No Place in the Black Liberation Movement," Critical Social Issues, Winter 1987
11. "Weight Lifting," December 5, 1988
12. "Not All the Panthers Were Men," September 2004
13. "Is There a Place in Our Movement?," n.d.
14. "The question of sexism…," n.d.
15. "So was it Just Another Liberal Fem. Affair?," n.d.
16. "Special Populations Caucus: Black Focus," n.d.
17. "Waking Dream," n.d.
18. "For Sale," n.d.
- SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIALS AND PHOTOGRAPHS
  - General (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Education (Box 1)
    - American University (Box 1)
      - Portfolio, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 2-4)
      - General, 1980, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Antioch College, 1973-82, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Daily activity log, 1997-2002 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Address books, undated (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
  - Directories, 1988-2004, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Appointment books, 1977-79 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  - Appointment books, 1980-2002 (Box 2, Folder 1-7)
  - Awards (Box 2)
    - General, 1988-97, undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Nomination for DC Women's Hall of Fame, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Memorials, eulogies, rites of passage, 1984-2014 (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
  - Events, 1988-2005, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Job search, 2000-04, undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Notes, 1984-2004, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Photographs, 1972-2013, undated (Box 3, Folder 2-3)
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE
  - General, 1988-2004, undated (Box 3, Folder 4-5)
  - Aishah Shahidah Simmons, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- SERIES III. CONFERENCES
  - General, 1982-2004, undated (Box 3, Folder 7-10)
  - First National Conference on Third World Women and Violence, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - I Am Your Sister, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - First National Conference on Black Women's Health Issues, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Fourth World Conference on Women, Nairobi, Kenya, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - National Conference on Violence Against Women of Color, 1987-88 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- SERIES IV. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS
  - African People's Socialist Party, 1979-81 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Black Panther Party (Box 4)
    - General, 1989-2005, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Scrapbook, circa 1968 (Box 4)
      - Photocopies (Box 4, Folder 5)
      - Originals (Box 4, Folder 6-8)
      - It's About Time - Alumni News, 1996-2001, undated (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - It's About Time-35th Anniversary Conference, 1998-2001 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Eddie Conway, 1997, undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Community for Creative Nonviolence (CCNV), 1992, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Counseling, 1998-2002, undated (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - D.C. Rape Crisis Center (Box 4)
    - General, 1980-2000, undated (Box 4, Folder 14-15)
    - Staying Safe, 1984, undated (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Child Sexual Abuse Curriculum, 1984, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Coalition for a Hassle Free Zone, 1984-89, undated (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Coalition for a Hassle Free Zone, 1985-86, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Anti Rape Week, 1980-86, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Press Clippings, 1979-89 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Pamphlets and publications, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - D.C. Study Group, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Global Economy Project, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Hannah House, 1992-2002, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - International Black Women's Congress, 1988-89, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - International Council of African Women (ICAW), 1984-90, undated (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
  - Kitchen Table Press, 1985-88, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - March for Women's Lives (Box 5)
    - General, 1989-2004, undated (Box 5, Folder 12-13)
    - Correspondence, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - New Voices Project, 2004, undated (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Million Women March, 1997-2005 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Nannie Helen Burroughs School and Covenant Early Childhood Learning Center, 1992-94, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - National Black United Front (Box 5)
    - General, 1985, undated (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Founding Convention Strategies, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 19-20)
  - National Black Women's Health Project (NBWHP, now Black Women's Health Imperative), 1987-93, undated (Box 5, Folder 21-22)
  - National Center for Human Rights Education (NCHRE) (Box 5)
    - General, 2004-05 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Correspondence, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Board of Directors Retreat, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 2-5)
    - Ford Foundation "Close to Home," 2004 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - People's Coalition for Justice, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Radio (Box 6)
    - Pacifica Network, 2004 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - WPFW (Box 6)
        - General, 1989-2005, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
        - International Women's Day, 1989-94, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
        - Sophie's Parlor Women's Radio Collective (Box 6)
          - General, 1998-2005, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
          - Correspondence: general, 2003-05 (Box 6, Folder 12)
          - Correspondence: package from Luci Murphy, undated (Box 6, Folder 13)
          - Playlists, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
          - International Women's Day, 2004, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
        - "In Our Voices" (Box 6)
          - General, 1988-2004, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
          - Scripts, 1988-98, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
          - Correspondence: general, 1988-2005 (Box 6, Folder 18)
          - Correspondence: promotional, 1999, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
          - Rape as a weapon of war, 2005, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
          - Refuse & Resist!, undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Regional Addiction Program (RAP), 1995-96, undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Save the People, 1974-76, undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - SisterSong Women of Color Reproductive Justice Collective (Box 7)
    - General, 2004, undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Management Circle meeting, 2005 (Box 7)
      - Mar 2005 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      - Jul 2005 (Box 7, Folder 8-9)
  - The SpiritHouse Project, 2005, undated (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Torture Abolition and Survivors Support Coalition (TASSC), 2004-05, undated (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Vanguard Services, undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Women for Women International, 2004-05, undated (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Youth Action Research Group (YARG), 1999, undated (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Yulanda Ward Memorial (Box 7)
    - General, 1980-85, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Fund, 1980-81 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Project: Black Women and Feminism, 1981, undated (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous, A-T (Box 7, Folder 18)
- SERIES V. SPEECHES AND WRITINGS
  - Speeches (Box 7)
    - A-P (Box 7, Folder 19-20)
    - R-V (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
    - Outlines, A-O (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Conference workshop outlines, E-W (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Writings, 1978-2004, undated (Box 8, Folder 5-6)
- SERIES VI. SUBJECT FILES
  - Abortion, 1988-2004, undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Activist tactics, undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Africa, 1980-2004 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - AIDS, 1987-89, undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Black history, 1974-94, undated (Box 8, Folder 11-13)
  - Black women and feminism (Box 8)
    - General, 1977-87, undated (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - SAGE Journal, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Cameroon, undated (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Central and South America, 1984-89, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Drugs, 1985-88, undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Health (Box 8)
    - General, 1983-2005 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Selected Articles on Black Women's Health, 1999 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - King, Rodney, 1992, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Labor, 1985-2004, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Million Man March, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 4-5)
  - Native American women, circa 1975-2004, undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Philippines, 1989, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Police and prison brutality, 1991-2005, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Poverty, 2004. n.d. (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Prostitution, 2004-05 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Resistance Conspiracy Case, 1989, undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Violence against women (Box 9)
    - General, 1984-2005, undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Third World women, 1988-89, undated (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Washington, D.C., 2002-04 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Welfare, 1990-93 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Woods, Dessie, 1981, undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Women (Box 9)
    - General, 1986-2005, undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Human rights, 1983-2005 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous, 1981-2005, undated (Box 9, Folder 19-20)
- SERIES VII. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS
  - Audiocassettes (Box 9)
    - "In Our Voices" (Box 9)
      - "Sheroes," 13 Feb 1990 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      - "Roe v. Wade," 24 Mar 1992 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      - "Grandmothering Due to Crack," 31 Mar 1992 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      - "Violence," 21 Apr 1992 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      - [Anacostia Cultural Center], 15 Sep 1992 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      - "Benito Torres 'Myth of Columbus'," 29 Sep 1992 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      - "Voting for Self-Determination," 3 Nov 1992 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      - "Jobs & Cultural Expression," 11 Nov 1992 (Box 10, Folder 8)
      - "Homelessness and Women," 5 Jan 1993 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - International Women's Day, 8 Mar 1993 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - "In Our Voices" (Box 10)
      - [Multiculturalism], 30 Mar 1993 (Box 10, Folder 11)
      - "Grace Paley," 18 May 1993 (Box 10, Folder 12)
      - "Depression," 25 May 1993 (Box 10, Folder 13)
      - "Women's Movement Part 1," 22 Jun 1993 (Box 10, Folder 14)
      - "Women's Movement Part 2," 22 Jun 1993 (Box 10, Folder 15)
      - "Housing Part 1," 14 Sep 1993 (Box 10, Folder 16)
      - "Reproductive Teq.," 17 Nov 199[?] (Box 10, Folder 17)
      - "Men's Roundtable, Gil Joyner," undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
      - "Faith Summit Pt II," undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - [Workshop Recording], "Cultural Imperialism," undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - [Workshop Recording], "Relationship Between African Women and Other Women of Color," undated (Box 10, Folder 21)